# TYLER STOTTS

455 Park Blvd East · 1204-890-6530

Tyler.stotts@hotmail.com · https://tysto.github.io/Master-Portfolio/#

A dedicated 26-year-old Computer Science Student. Known for my innovative ideas and creativity towards my co-workers and clients. Widely recognized for my dedication, experience in the work field and incredibly hard work. In addition to my goal-orientation and hard work, I certainly believe my skills are useful for the work field.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **OCTOBER 2021 - CURRENT**

# **FREELANCING**

- Engineered scalable, responsive, multi-platform and SEO friendly websites using HTML5 CCS3, Javascript ES6+ and React
- Competent towards user's experience
- Connected to backend API's through Axios CRUD HTTP requests
- Tasked to make up-to-date websites for various clients.
- Concept and develop unique styles and animations

#### **NOVEMBER 2021 - CURRENT**

#### PRIVATE PROGRAMING TUTOR

- Tutored clients HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Conveyed distinctive style of teaching.
- Assisted students around the world.
- Ability to task students on strengthening coding skills.

#### **JANUARY 2022 - CURRENT**

#### **DIGI-PAID**

- Working to launch a crypto currency/wallet on WEB3.
- Work with a team of elite engineers on frontend development.
- Assist when needed with backend development.
- Ability to work as a team as well as be mentored by Senior Engineers

# **EDUCATION**

**JULY 2021** 

FRONTEND ENGINEERING SIMPLIFIED, ONLINE

**SEPTEMBER 2021** 

HARVARD CS50 COMPUTER SCIENCE, ONLINE

# **SKILLS**

- HTML5
- JavaScript
- CSS
- React
- Firebase
- Node.JS
- GitHub
- React dev tools
- Redux